

Filipe Santos

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Technical Skills

HTML, CSS, SCSS,
Javascript, Typescript,
React, React Native, Next.js,
Node.js, Express.js, Redux,
C/C++, Java,
Android SDK,
SQL, SQLite, MongoDB,
Docker, Kubernetes.

Soft Skills

Solutions & Results Oriented, Deep Thinking & analysis, Task & fact-oriented, Focus & attention to detail.

Languages

English C1
French B2

Portuguese Native

Contact

Phone +41 78 211 95 96

Email fd.filipe@gmail.com

Resident Permit B

LinkedIn in/filipedsantos

Portfolio https://portfolio-fsantos.netlify.app

Address Ch. du nant-de-crève-coeur 10

1290 Versoix

Profile

A fast-learning, curious, and diligent IT specialist using my skills in software development. Today my focus is to improve my skills in the frontend, with proficiencies in HTML/CSS, and Javascript, I've been using React and React Native framework to create different types of projects, not only for the Web but also for mobile (Android & IOS).

Professional Experience

Front-End Developer Freelancer, 02/2022 - Present

- Work with stakeholders to gather and refine specifications and requirements based on technical needs,
- Create layouts and user interfaces,
- Develop and deploy projects into production,
- HTML, CSS, JS, React.js, React Native, Typescript.

Full-Stack Developer, GBN, 03/2022 - 08/2022

Concepting and creating a RESTful API, developed with Node.js, Express.js, and MongoDB to manage the hardware requests to the IT department.

- Analyze and define the scope of the project,
- Create documentation and mockups to create foundations,
- Explore technologies to achieve all project objectives,
- Release application to production,
- Javascript, HTML, CSS, PUG, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Docker.

Android Developer, Ciengis S.A., 09/2017 - 02/2018

Creating and developing a Dashboard application for the Android ecosystem, to complete the company products.

- Analyze and define the scope of the project,
- Create documentation and mockups to create foundations,
- Set goals and objectives to be met within a time frame,
- Unit, integration, and acceptance testing,
- JAVA, Android Studio, OPC UA.

Education

React Native - The Practical Guide [2023]

Udemy, November 2022

React - The Complete Guide (incl Hooks, React Router, Redux)

Udemy, October 2022

Node.js, Express & MongoDB Bootcamp

Udemy, May 2022

The Complete JavaScript Course 2023: From Zero to Expert!

Udemy, April 2022

B.S. Computer Science & Mathematics

Instituto Superior de Engenharia de Coimbra, July 2018